#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/vasuki-r-bb0b8619 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
Cloud Computing
Cloud Foundry

#### Languages

English (Professional Working)
Tamil

#### Certifications

Getting Started with Containers on IBM Cloud

Getting started with Microservices with Istio and IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service

AWS Certified Solutions Architect IBM Agile Advocate IBM Agile Explorer

# Vasuki R

DevOps Engineer at GovTech Singapore Singapore

## Summary

I am a Cloud computing Solutions Architect, certified by AWS on the same . I am currently involved in Analysis, Designing, Planning and Implementation of Cloud environment and DevOps implementations. I can lead a whole project of Cloud migration and DevOps implementations which I am doing right now . Cloud Migration can be to both private and public cloud, or even hybrid cloud, depending on Client's needs.

My experience background is on Application development and also on Infrastructure. I have had good hands-on experience in designing and implementing complex CI/CD pipelines.

#### Technical skills:

Cloud environment - IBM Bluemix / Cloud Foundry, Amazon Web Services(Amazon EC2,S3, Auto scaling, Route 53, VPC, Amazon Cloud formation, Cloudwatch), Openstack

DevOps Skills - CI/CD, Kubernetes, Chef, Puppet, Ansible Version Control Systems - CVS, Subversion, Git, Artifactory Automation/Build Tools - Travis, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, UCD Languages & Scripting - Python, Java, Ruby, Shell scripting, Maven, JSP, XPath & XSLT

Web Technologies - Responsive Web Design, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery and libraries, JSON, XML, RSS, Microsoft Visio

Development & Design Tools - RAD, RSA, Eclipse, NetBeans, SQL Developer, Jira and Visual Studio code

Tools New Relic, Pager Duty, SendGrid, IBM FileNet P8 Application Engine, Process Engine & Content Engine,

Testing tool - SonarQube, Selenium, Junit, JMeter

Application & Web Servers - WebLogic, WebSphere, Tomcat, JBoss, Apache, IBM HIS, Nginx

Databases & Technologies - Oracle, MySQL, SQL, Cloudant, Mongo DB

Operating System - Red Hat Enterprise Linux, IBM AIX, MS Windows

#### Virtualization - VMware VM, IBM KVM

\* Please ask for resume for more details on my work experience.

# Experience

GovTech Singapore
DevOps Engineer
July 2019 - Present (1 year 9 months)
Singapore

#### **IBM**

11 years 8 months

DevOps Engineer August 2016 - Present (4 years 8 months) Singapore

- Sole responsibility for solution designing of migration from legacy model to cloud model for 3 IBM clients
- Represented various discussions involving the demonstration of proposed Cloud models
- Installation, Configuration and setup of IBM Cloud Orchestrator (ICO) Openstack
- Implemented DevOps tools (Git, Jenkins, UCD) for CI/CD automation
- Automated numerous Infrastructure management tasks using Chef
- Code migration of Legacy application from physical server to Github repository
- Setting up the cloud infrastructure for the application in Bluemix
- Drove the Move to Cloud initiative for the Integration Services hub in Asia
   Pacific which hosted more than 100+ Integrations, to make use of the IBM
   SoftLayer's laaS cloud offering
- Migrate Client's infrastructure and applications to AWS platform
- Plan Create and Deploy cloud Infrastructure/Environments using AWS EC2, ELB, VPC, RDS, Route 53, AWC CLI, IAM, CloudWatch based on customer/ Internal requirements
- Create and Deploy cloud Infrastructure/Environments "stacks" using AWS CloudFormation service
- Infrastructure Automation using AWS CloudFormation stacks
- Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment in IBM Cloud Foundry(Bluemix) using UCD

- Architecture and develop Docker-based infrastructure
- Developing Docker image for deploying the components in Kubernetes
- Developing scripts for build, deployment, maintenance and related tasks using Travis, Docker, Maven, Python and Bash
- Created automated scripts using JSON,YAML and Python for infrastructure as code
- Create process for the deployment in UCD
- Installation, Configuration and setup of IBM OpenStack
- Written Heat templates as per the demands from various departments
- Migrating the current infrastructure resources to be managed by IBM OpenStack
- Written cookbooks in Chef for various Infrastructure implementations
- Infrastructure Automation using scripts and DevOps tools like Chef, Git etc

## Cloud Engineer

January 2016 - Present (5 years 3 months)

Singapore

Developer - Enterprise Integration Services August 2009 - December 2015 (6 years 5 months) Singapore

#### SATYAM COMPUTER SERVICES, LTD

Developer

March 2006 - August 2009 (3 years 6 months)

Chennai Area, India

# Education

Anna University

BE, ECE · (2001 - 2005)

Seventh Day Adventist School

 $\cdot$  (2001)